<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Hello World with Ceylon">

	<intro>
		<description>
			This cheat sheet shows you how to create a new Ceylon project, a
			Ceylon compilation unit contained in that project, and finally run
			the Ceylon program.
		</description>
	</intro>

	<item title="Open the Ceylon Perspective" skip="true">
		<action pluginId="org.eclipse.ui.cheatsheets"
			class="org.eclipse.ui.internal.cheatsheets.actions.OpenPerspective"
			param1="com.redhat.ceylon.eclipse.ui.perspective" />
		<description>
			We need to be in the Ceylon Perspective. Select
			<b>Window > Open Perspective > Other ... > Ceylon</b> from the menu bar at the
			top of the workbench, or click below. (If you're already in the
			Ceylon perspective, you can skip this step.)
		</description>
	</item>

	<item title="Create a Ceylon project" dialog="true">
		<description>
			First, we&apos;ll create a project using the New Ceylon Project
			wizard. Select 
			<b>File > New > Ceylon Project</b> or click below.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Call the project "hello", or whatever you like, and click 
			<b>Finish</b>.
		</description>
		<command required="false"
			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.newWizard(newWizardId=com.redhat.ceylon.eclipse.ui.newProjectWizard)" />
	</item>

	<item title="Create a Ceylon compilation unit" dialog="true">
		<description>
			Next, we&apos;ll need a Ceylon source file, which we'll create
			using the New Ceylon Source File wizard. Select
			<b>File > New > Ceylon Source File</b> or click below.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Call the unit "hello", or whatever you like, select the option
			<b>Create toplevel class or method declaration</b>, choose the 
			source folder of the project we just created, and finally click 
			<b>Finish</b>.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Note that if you give the compilation unit an initial lowercase
			name, the wizard will fill in a method declaration. If you give
			it an initial uppercase name, the wizard will fill in a class 
			declaration. For the purposes of this tutorial, it doesn't really 
			matter which.
		</description>
		<command required="false"
			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.newWizard(newWizardId=com.redhat.ceylon.eclipse.ui.newUnitWizard)" />
	</item>

	<item title="Add the code to the method">
		<description>
			Next, in the Ceylon editor that opened automatically, add the
			following code to the body of the "hello" method (or "Hello"
			class):
			<br/>
			<br/>
			<b>print("hello world");</b>
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Then, add a <b>shared</b> annotation to the method or class to
			mark it as runnable.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Remember to save the file.
		</description>
	</item>

	<item title="Run the program">
		<description>
			Now let's run the program. Select the project or compilation
			unit in the Ceylon Explorer and select
			<b>Run > Run As > Ceylon Java Application</b>.
			You should see the message in the console.
		</description>
	</item>

</cheatsheet>
