<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Introduction to Ceylon Modules">

    <intro>
        <description>
            This cheat sheet shows you how to create a new Ceylon project, a
            Ceylon module contained in that project, add a dependency to a 
            Ceylon platform module in Ceylon Herd, and finally export the
            module to an external Ceylon module repository. You will need
            an Internet connection to connect to Herd.
        </description>
    </intro>

    <item title="Open the Ceylon Perspective" skip="true">
        <action pluginId="org.eclipse.ui.cheatsheets"
            class="org.eclipse.ui.internal.cheatsheets.actions.OpenPerspective"
            param1="com.redhat.ceylon.eclipse.ui.perspective" />
        <description>
            We need to be in the Ceylon Perspective. Select
            <b>Window > Open Perspective > Other ... > Ceylon</b> from the menu bar at the
            top of the workbench, or click below. (If you're already in the
            Ceylon perspective, you can skip this step.)
        </description>
    </item>

    <item title="Create a Ceylon project" dialog="true">
        <description>
            First, we&apos;ll create a project using the New Ceylon Project
            wizard. Select 
            <b>File > New > Ceylon Project</b> or click below.
            <br/>
            <br/>
            Call the project "dice", or whatever you like, and click 
            <b>Finish</b>.
        </description>
        <command required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.newWizard(newWizardId=com.redhat.ceylon.eclipse.ui.newProjectWizard)" />
    </item>

    <item title="Create a Ceylon module" dialog="true">
        <description>
            Next, we&apos;ll create the Ceylon module using the New Ceylon 
            Module wizard. Select
            <b>File > New > Ceylon Module</b> or click below.
            <br/>
            <br/>
            Call the module "dice", or whatever you like, choose the source 
            folder of the project we just created, and finally click 
            <b>Finish</b>.
        </description>
        <command required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.newWizard(newWizardId=com.redhat.ceylon.eclipse.ui.newModuleWizard)" />
    </item>

    <item title="Add a module dependency">
        <description>
            Open the file "module.ceylon", and add the following line to
            the module descriptor, just before the closing brace:
            <br/>
            <br/>
            <b>import ceylon.math "1.1.0";</b>
            <br/>
            <br/>
            Remember to save the file. You may have to adjust the version number here to the 
            version number of Ceylon you are using. <b>ceylon.math</b> is part of the Ceylon SDK 
            and has the same versioning scheme as the language.
            <br/>
            <br/>
            Alternatively, you can add this dependency by selecting your
            module in the Ceylon Explorer and then selecting
            <b>File > Properties</b>, selecting <b>Ceylon Module</b>, 
            clicking <b>Add imports...</b>, and choosing the module "ceylon.math" in the popup
            dialog. 
        </description>
    </item>

    <item title="Add code to the run method">
        <description>
            Next, in the Ceylon editor that opened automatically, add the
            following "import" statement, at the top of the file:
            <br/>
            <br/>
            <b>import ceylon.math.float { random }</b>
            <br/>
            <br/>
            Now add the following code to the body of the "run" method:
            <br/>
            <br/>
            <b>print("You rolled ``(random()*6).integer+1`` ``(random()*6).integer+1``");</b>
            <br/>
            <br/>
            Remember to save the file.
        </description>
    </item>

    <item title="Export the module" dialog="true">
        <description>
            Finally, select the project in the Ceylon Explorer and select 
            <b>File > Export... > Ceylon > Ceylon Module to Module Repository</b>
            or click below.
            <br/>
            <br/>
            Choose the project we just created, and a Ceylon module repository 
            on your filesystem. Click <b>Finish</b> to export our new module to 
            the module repository.
            <br/>
            <br/> 
            If you have installed the Ceylon command line tools (and the paths to 
            Ceylon runtime and repository are correctly set), you can  
            run the module via the systems command line: 
            <br/>
            <br/>
            <b>ceylon run dice</b>
        </description>
        <command
              required="false"
              serialization="org.eclipse.ui.file.export(exportWizardId=com.redhat.ceylon.eclipse.ui.exportModuleWizard)"/>
    </item>

</cheatsheet>
